Shubert-Garrick-Belasco Theatre 072
People's Archive, MLK Library
Shubert-Garrick-Belasco Theatre Collection
1918-1934
People's Archive, MLK Library
Shubert-Garrick Theatre (Organization: Washington, D.C.)
Shubert-Belasco Theatre (Organization: Washington, D.C.)
Poli's Theatre (Washington, D.C.)
072
2 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Shubert Theatres were owned by the Shubert Brothers of New York. The Shubert brothers, Lee, Sam and Jacob, owned theatres throughout the United States, including Washington, DC D.C. They originally staged operettas and then moved on to staging musicals and dramas in the 1930s and 1940s. Originally created as Shubert Enterprises, the Shubert Organization still manages theatres throughout the U.S., including the National Theatre in the District. The Shuberts managed the Garrick Theatre, the Belasco Theatre and Poli's Theatre in the District from the 1910s to the 1930s. After examining the programs from these three theatres, it is assumed that the Garrick Theatre ceased in existence around 1925. By that year, the Shuberts produced one program for both the Belasco Theatre and Poli's Theatre.
Custodial History
The collection was accessioned into the Library in 1998. However, documentation indicates that it had been a part of the Archives before 1997. The donor is unknown.
Related Materials
Artificial and Ephemeral Collection (Collection 60) Violet Lowens DC Culture Collection (Collection 90) David Kiefer Theatre Collection (Collection 118)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of five bound volumes of financial records from the Shubert-Garrick Theatre and the Shubert-Belasco Theatre. These records show the expenses and financial reports for various productions from 1918 to 1934.
Performing Arts; Account books; Theatres
- Series 1
  - Bound Volume - Shubert-Garrick Weekly Statements, January 1918-May 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bound Volume - Shubert-Garrick Weekly Statements, October 1919-May 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bound Volume - Shubert-Garrick Weekly Statements, September 1920-May 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bound Volume - Shubert Advanced Vaudeville Circuit Inc., Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bound Volume - Shubert-Belasco Weekly Statements, October 1921-April 1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bound Volume - Shubert-Belasco Weekly Statements, September 1925-June 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Programs - Garrick, 1919-1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Programs - Garrick, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Account Book - Belasco, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Checks - Belasco, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Film Contracts - Belasco, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programs - Belasco, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ticket Stubs - Belasco, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Weekly Statements - Belasco, December 1928-November 1929 (Box 2, Folder 8)